<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>AI From Scratch Blog</title>
        <link>https://ai-ml-dev.github.io/aiml-from-scratch/blog</link>
        <description>AI From Scratch Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Micro:bit Machines!]]></title>
            <link>https://ai-ml-dev.github.io/aiml-from-scratch/blog/unbox-microbit</link>
            <guid>unbox-microbit</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[What is the Micro:Bit?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>What is the Micro:Bit?</h2><p>According to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Micro_Bit">Wikipedia</a> the <code>micro:bit</code> (or BBC Micro Bit) is <em>an open-source hardware ARM-based embedded system designed by the BBC for use in computer education in the United Kingdom</em>. </p><h3>Micro:Bit - v2</h3><p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Micro_Bit#v2">v2</a> was released in Oct 2020 - marking a turning point in both the hardware support available, and the strong ecosystem of tools, languages and curriculum that exist for programming applications using it.</p><p><img src="/img/microbit-v2.jpeg" alt="Micro:Bit v2"/></p><p> The v2 board contains the following hardware components:</p><ul><li>A 16 MHz 32-bit ARM Cortex-M0 microcontroller, USB 2.0</li><li>A 5x5 pixel display (made with 25 LEDs)</li><li>Sensors - 3-axis accelerometer, 3-axis magnetometer, touch, temperature</li><li>Inputs - 3 push buttons (2 for apps, 1 for reset)</li><li>Audio - magnetic speaker, microphone (with built-in LED indicator)</li><li>2.4 GHz Bluetooth networking.</li></ul><h3>Coding Environments</h3><p>The default coding environments supported are:</p><ul><li><a href="https://microbit.org/code/#microsoft-makecode">Microsoft MakeCode</a> - block-based</li><li><a href="https://microbit.org/code/#python">Python Editor</a> - text-based</li><li><a href="https://microbit.org/code/#scratch">MIT Scratch</a> - block-based</li><li><a href="https://microbit.org/get-started/user-guide/mobile/#makecode-apps">Android/iOS Apps</a> - MakeCode programs over Bluetooth</li><li><a href="https://microbit.org/get-started/user-guide/mobile/#swift-playgrounds">Swift Playground</a> - interactive book, Mac/iPad</li></ul><p>But there are also a number of <a href="https://microbit.org/code/#other-editors">community-supported editors</a> to explore - including <a href="http://appinventor.mit.edu/">MIT AppInventor</a>, a platform for building Android and iPhone apps - which supports <a href="http://iot.appinventor.mit.edu/#/microbit/microbitintro">micro:bit extensions</a> to enable mobile app interactions with the micro:bit.</p><p>Code can be downloaded (flashed) onto the device over the physical USB connection, or over Bluetooth (from mobile devices). On compliant browsers (e.g., Chrome and Edge on desktop) you can transfer code directly from the coding environment over <a href="https://microbit.org/get-started/user-guide/web-usb/">Web USB</a> making the develop-deploy experience incredibly easy - especially for kids.</p><h3>Coding Languages</h3><p>The most popular tutorials use block-based environments (MakeCode or Scratch) and we already know you can code with Python or Swift. But it turns out there are a number of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Micro_Bit#Software">other programming languages</a> you can use - including C++, Rust, and BASIC.</p><h3>Unboxing micro:bit v2</h3><p>To get started I got <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Vilros-BBC-Micro-Basic-Starter/dp/B08WR4X7P9/">this basic micro:bit v2 bundle</a> from Amazon. Unboxed, you can see it contains the microcontroller board, a battery holder, a protective case, a USB2.0 cable - and some crocodile clips.</p><p><img src="/img/microbit-unboxed.jpg" alt="Microbit-v2"/></p><p>This was sufficient to get us started with the basic <a href="https://makecode.microbit.org/">&quot;Flashing Hearts&quot;</a> tutorial - and validate that the board was in fact working as advertised. <code>Bonus:</code> we used webUSB for all our downloads - and it was beautiful!!</p><p>That was it for today. Tomorrow, we do this all over again - this time with <a href="https://scratch.mit.edu/microbit">Scratch</a> - so we can learn how to work with both these block-based coding environments before we move on to text editors and more features.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title>
            <link>https://ai-ml-dev.github.io/aiml-from-scratch/blog/hello-world</link>
            <guid>hello-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to the AI From Scratch website and blog.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the <em>AI From Scratch</em> website and blog. </p><p>This a pair programming and collaborative learning project from me (Nitya, the parent) and my son (AJ, the middle-schooler) as we attempt to explore the fascinating world of machine learning and artificial intelligence in a youth-friendly way.</p><p>We&#x27;re still setting things up so do come back later to see our progress.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>